♪Mighty winds carry me to the heavens♪
♪On a wild steed,
I sing, smiling at the mortal world♪
♪Then the cold night veils the stars♪
♪I fall to the depths, yet walk alone♪
♪I brave countless snowy peaks♪
♪Your lingering warmth still fills
my palm♪
♪Though frost and snow may bar my way♪
♪The light in my eyes will never fade♪
♪With a sword that cleaves the clouds♪
♪With a heart as firm as stone♪
♪Through all I've endured,
I have no regrets♪
♪I'm still the boy I once was♪
=Sword God=
=Episode 15=
Greetings, Honglian Sword Immortal.
You were pretty defiant before.
Now you know how to bow?
Well, I need a favor from you.
How could I not bow my head?
Good.
You certainly know
what you like and dislike.
I like it.
Where are the other two Sword Immortals?
What?
Am I
not enough for you?
No, no!
I was just asking after them.
Your cultivation is too weak.
If all three of us taught you together,
you might never master any of it
in your lifetime.
So we'll take turns.
If you can't even grasp my teaching,
then forget about meeting the other two.
Of course,
I quite like you.
But I can't keep teaching you forever.
So,
you've got three days.
If I'm satisfied with your progress,
you can stay.
If you can't,
then leave.
I'll do my best.
What level is your cultivation now?
Sword Immortal,
Spirit Burst Realm, Stage 9.
In just over half a year,
you've already reached Stage 9?
Even if you were gifted,
given that you started over,
how could you advance so fast?
(Spirit Burst Realm, Stage 9)
Not bad.
So you absorbed all the energy
from that old man's spirit vein.
Your Dao Bone is quite interesting.
But let me warn you.
That old man from Sword Immortal Inn
holds a grudge.
If you ever run into him,
just escape.
Yeah, I'd better.
Come with me.
These are the swords
we three have collected
over the centuries.
You can't practice swordsmanship
without a sword.
Even the lowest-grade ones here
are mid-grade spirit weapons.
Pick any one you like.
Want some recommendations?
This one is Mystique.
It's light and nimble.
It cuts through the air silently
and kills without a trace.
Perfect for surprise attacks.
This one is Fine Snow.
Forged from Tianshan cold iron.
It carries the power of ice.
It can slow down an enemy's weapon,
giving you an edge in battle.
This is the Mystic Iron Greatsword.
It's incredibly powerful
and nearly indestructible.
It's just a little on the heavy side.
But you're a man.
A little extra weight won't hurt.
It suits your style, too.
Nothing works for you?
Aren't you usually decisive?
Why are you suddenly so indecisive?
Immortal Venerable,
I...
I like that one!
That one won't do.
You said I could pick any one.
Why can't I have that one?
Any but that one.
The rest are yours to choose from.
Forget it, then.
I'll just find a branch out there.
It'll do.
(My storage ring)
(is full of ordinary spirit weapons.)
(But this sword)
(makes me want it so badly.)
Why are you so stubborn?
You just won't listen.
You said I could pick.
I don't like any of the others.
What now?
This sword is called Solitude.
It's a relic left by our master,
an ancient demonic sword.
It can consume the wielder's mind.
Even my master, a mighty cultivator,
was not immune.
For a thousand years
after my master's death,
no one has been able to wield it.
I want to try.
But I'm warning you.
This sword seems to be cursed.
Not only can it consume
its wielder's mind,
it can also bring misfortune upon them,
and even hurt those around them.
That's why it's called Solitude.
Misfortune?
I've got a blood feud to settle.
My entire family was slaughtered.
How could I possibly care
about misfortune?
Fine.
Since you refuse to give up,
give it a try.
But I must warn you.
Solitude is sentient.
It can choose its own master.
For a thousand years, great cultivators
have come to the island for it.
Not one has succeeded.
So,
don't get your hopes up.
Something's wrong.
Stop!
Stay back!
It's reading my memories.
It's fine.
I can take it.
I told you it wouldn't work.
Why ask for trouble...?
♪With a sword that cleaves the clouds♪
♪With a heart as firm as stone♪
♪Through all I've endured,
I have no regrets♪
♪I'm still the boy I once was♪
Solitude.
It really is a fine sword.
How is this possible?
Immortal Venerable,
this sword
is mine now.
(In theory,)
(he shouldn't even qualify
to come to Sword Immortal Island.)
(He started over)
(and received Bai Xi's help.)
(Now he has made it here)
(and Solitude has chosen him.)
(Everything seems like a coincidence,)
(yet somehow, it feels like fate.)
Looks like congratulations are in order.
Let's go.
We agreed on three days.
Two days remain.
How much you learn is up to you.
(Three Days Later)
Heavenburn Sword Shadow!
Crimson Flash of the Swan!
Heaven-Splitting Strike!
(Good heavens!)
(For an ordinary cultivator,)
(even thirty years might not
be enough to master half a move.)
(Yet he mastered all three sword arts)
(to minor mastery in just three days.)
(What a monster!)
Are you satisfied
with my swordsmanship,
Immortal Venerable?
Catch this wine!
It's brewed from Cold Spring water.
It's incredibly potent.
Drink it.
Then train while the wine takes effect.
Immortal Venerable,
I can't hold my liquor.
If I get drunk,
how can I train?
Once you drink it,
if you can burn off the alcohol
through swordplay,
it'll temper your body,
and toughen your physique
even more.
As you command.
♪How many rains must pass♪
♪Before someone comes to me?♪
♪To spend this life with you♪
♪A faint new moon, a touch of iris blue♪
♪How deep the dreams♪
Train!
♪Can three more lives see us through?♪
♪East winds shift, snows remain♪
♪Joy and pain, what fate ordains?♪
♪Brush in hand, my joy, my pain♪
Letting go of your sword
is a swordsman's greatest taboo.
But, Immortal Venerable,
this wine...
It's too strong.
Clear your mind.
The Sword intent is you.
You're the sword intent.
Even drunk,
even wounded,
even dying,
the sword must not stop!
♪Can three more lives see us through?♪
♪East winds shift, snows remain♪
♪Joy and pain, what fate ordains?♪
♪Brush in hand, my joy, my pain♪
♪With moonlight in my cup,
I drink my longing♪
♪For the rest of my life,
whose face will I seek?♪
♪Rouge-stained tears deepen
the wounds I bear.♪
♪In less than an instant,
how could love fall apart?♪
♪I ask the world,
as blood blooms into flowers♪
♪When petals fall,
whose obsession can't be severed?♪
♪Falling from the cliff♪
Though one sword can split the sky,
life is still but emptiness.
I roam the heavens, draining
a hundred cups to drown worldly dreams.
I laugh at life's fleeting beauty.
♪I ask the world,
as blood blooms into flowers♪
(In just an instant,)
(he entered a state of selflessness.)
(He's really a monster.)
♪To tie our hair as one♪
How do you feel?
Still drunk?
I've never felt this peaceful before.
What cultivation art do you practice?
Immortal Venerable,
I practice my family's
Primordial Dao Art.
Nonsense!
That's only a human-tier
cultivation art of the lowest grade.
How could you be so talented
while practicing an art like that?
I don't know.
My father always told me
it has been passed down in our family.
(It really is the Primordial Dao Art.)
(No.)
(Its source seems
to be the Primordial Dao Art.)
(But the details are different.)
(It's almost like...)
What is it, Immortal Venerable?
Nothing.
You've trained well.
As for swordsmanship,
I have nothing left to teach you.
Thanks for your guidance
these three days.
However,
I may have another way
to raise your cultivation.
What way?
I obtained a secret manual
about dual cultivation.
It lets both partners serve
as cultivation vessels.
Dual...
Dual cultivation?
♪I once stood on high,
drawing spiritual energy into my blade♪
♪I laughed, pointing at the stars,
young and fearless♪
♪Then came my fall,
with frost and snow on my shoulders♪
♪My Dao foundation was damaged,
yet my Dao heart never wavered♪
♪I crossed countless peaks
to find my answer again♪
♪Through endless trials,
my Nascent Soul came♪
♪Heaven and earth my furnace,
I rose from the flame♪
♪No sword in hand,
yet numberless blades obey♪
♪I seek the Dao beyond the clouds♪
♪Unafraid of countless trials♪
♪With this flesh and soul♪
♪I shall forge a new age♪
♪Let thunder and fire crown me♪
♪Let wind and clouds heed me♪
♪At cultivation's peak♪
♪My first resolve remains unchanged♪
♪The sun and moon turn♪
♪I hear the Great Dao ring♪
♪I am the undying flame♪
♪Looking back when dust settles♪
♪At last I see, immortality♪
♪Lives in your smiles♪